# Tony Gama

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- 1. Developed a Full Stack Application with .NET and React
- 2. Developed ETL pipelines and automation scripts in Python
- 3. Architected and deployed scalable solutions on Azure PaaS/laaS
- 4. Reduced Development Time of New Features by 50%
- 5. Launched 5 Projects Utilizing Different Tech Stacks

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Apr 2022 – PRESENT Plego Technologies

- Led the development of a legal contract management platform utilizing C# and .NET to migrate a legacy system to a modern SPA architecture, achieving a 30% performance improvement.
- Developed ETL pipelines and automation scripts in Python for data engineering, analysis and AI/ML projects involving NLP, CV and predictive modeling.
- Architected and deployed scalable solutions on Azure PaaS/laaS leveraging services like App Services, SQL, Cosmos DB, Functions and Kubernetes.
- Developed a new component in React that was used to define complex conditions based on field values, used throughout the application in many features.
- Oversaw the creation of coding standards and started a discussion about code quality management in the company.
- Developed features in ASP.NET Core RESTful API, Azure Functions, and Angular apps.
- Developed software that extracted data from hundreds of thousands of PDF documents about insurance plans, then organized the extracted data to provide reports to business owners.

Technologies: ASP.NET, Web API 2, React, Vue, SCSS, Agile, SQL, RabbitMQ, Zoho API, CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, Git, HTML5, .NET Core, C#.NET, APIs, Front-end, Full-stack, Architecture, REST APIs, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

## **FULL-STACK DEVELOPER**

Apr 2021 – Apr 2022 Tempora

- Used C#, the .NET Framework, Microsoft SQL Server, Node.js, and AngularJS to write robust APIs and components that scale.
- Worked on creating tools that set up the supply pipeline—finding builders with the skills that clients needed.
- Worked on the pipeline efficiency to process files with thousands of lines efficiently and asynchronously, using microservices and 3rd-party services.

#### CONTACT

tonygmstar@gmail.com (713) 955-7635 www.linkedin.com/in/tonygama-fullstack Houston, TX

## **ABOUT ME**

A full-stack web developer who started with .NET as his chosen back-end framework and, more recently, worked mainly with Node.js and Python. Proficient in React, Vue and Angular. Am a quick learner, willing and able to learn new skills rapidly, and is experienced in working in a multinational environment. Have cooperated with teams and clients from US and various European countries.

## **EDUCATION**

St. Edward's University, 2018 Master's in Computer Science

University of Texas at Dallas, 2015 Bachelor's in Computer Science

- Developed a front-end internal tooling platform in React to give access to all the tools the team built to the other employees in the company.
- Migrated AngularJS SPA to React and Redux, improving performance significantly.
- Designed and developed key parts of an API gateway and nine microservices based on ASP.NET Core, backed by PostgreSQL and deployed in a Kubernetes cluster.
- Provided technical expertise and insights to direct troubleshooting efforts and solution development.

Technologies: Node.js, TypeScript, PHP, RabbitMQ, React, Angular, Express.js, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Kubernetes, CSS, JavaScript, Git, HTML5, Redux, Frontend, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, Tailwind CSS, OAuth, Architecture, Redux Toolkit, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Best Practices, Python, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

## SENIOR REACT, VUE, ANGULAR, AND .NET DEVELOPER

May 2018 – Apr 2021 TekRevol

- Developed core features and dashboards for the merchant portal of Gyapu e-commerce marketplace using React with Redux and Styled Components on the front-end, while also implementing order processing and payment APIs using ASP.NET and PostgreSQL on the back-end, helping thousands of small businesses to efficiently manage product listings, orders and inventory on the platform.
- Developed and maintained both front-end and back end layer of Parts Source's platform using C#, .NET and React.
- Cooperated with the designers and back-end developers to ensure the proper quality of the provided solution.
- Implemented server-side rendering for the React application using C#, the .NET Core SPA Services functionality.
- Developed the intake module using C#, .NET Core, GraphQL, and REST API.
- Provided UI expertise with Angular and React to troubleshoot existing UI problems and build new user-friendly forms—revamping the user experience.
- Reduced the size of the data access layer by 50%.
- Introduced automated E2E testing to facilitate regression testing for each push to QA.
- Maintained and developed a Microsft SQL database and an API in Node.js that utilized this database.
- Refactored a legacy service that processed weather data written in C#.
- Mentored the team and enforced Scrum principles, ensuring the Scrum process's quality.

Technologies: React, .NET, Vue, Angular, Redux, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Git, Agile, HTML5, ASP.NET Web API, .NET Core, C#.NET, Front-end, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, OAuth, REST APIs, Azure DevOps, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

### .NET WEB DEVELOPER

Apr 2017 – May 2018 Screenlink Technologies

- Implemented the database logic and APIs to support a new pricing model for TotalJobs Recruiter Platform, the UK's largest job site. Built the front end in React and the back end in C#, .NET Web API 2.
- Refactored the existing code to use design patterns and best practices.
- Developed a service in .NET Core to be used for new pricing model calculations.

## **SKILLS**

#### Languages

TypeScript, CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, C#, HTML, C#.NET, SQL, SCSS, Python, PHP

#### **Frameworks**

.NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET Web API, Entity, Swagger, Angular, ADO.NET, Node.js, Express.js, Redux, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, ASP.NET Core, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET MVC 5, Knockout (Knockout.js), Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), ASP.NET

#### Libraries/APIs

Vue, Vue 2, Node.js, React, REST APIs, jQuery, AutoMapper, Zoho API, Entity Framework, Web API 2

#### **Tools**

Git, Bitbucket, Jenkins, TeamCity, Azure DevOps Services, Jira, Visual Studio, Gulp, RabbitMQ

#### **Paradigms**

Agile, Scrum, REST, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), FluentValidation, Azure DevOps

#### **Platforms**

Visual Studio Code (VS Code), Software Design Patterns, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Azure, Windows, Kubernetes

#### Other

MVC Frameworks, WCF Web Services, GitFlow, APIs, Front-end, Front-end Development, Full-stack, CI/CD Pipelines, Episerver, Cloud, User Interface (UI), OAuth, Architecture, Redux Toolkit, Octopus Deploy

## Storage

MSSQLCE, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, IBM Db2

- Created and enforced coding standards which ensured the quality of solutions developed by the team.
- Ensured the high quality of the development solution by proposing and implementing code quality enhancements.

Technologies: Octopus Deploy, TeamCity, jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, ASP.NET Core, CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, Git, Agile, Scrum, HTML5, ASP.NET Web API, C#.NET, CI/CD Pipelines, OAuth, REST APIs, Best Practices, Object-oriented Programming (OOP), Software Design Patterns

### **ASSOCIATE DEVELOPER**

Aug 2016 – Apr 2017 Screenlink Technologies

- Maintained and conducted workshops for a desktop application facilitating the financial reporting process.
- Developed multiple web apps used for gathering financial data from users.
- Contributed to the statutory financial audit as an auditor, gaining knowledge about accounting processes.
- Learned how to write performant and robust business logic using Microsoft SQL Server and .NET Framework.
- Worked with a systems engineer to gain an understanding of network security and maintainable infrastructure, including AWS.

Technologies: jQuery, Microsoft SQL Server, Entity Framework, ASP.NET MVC, Windows Communication Framework (WCF), Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), CSS, .NET, JavaScript, C#, HTML5, C#.NET, Front-end, Full-stack, REST APIs, Object-oriented Programming (OOP)

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

## **SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT**

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate Web Applications Microsoft

#### **AUGUST 2018 - AUGUST 2013**

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer Web Applications Microsoft

# JULY 2018 - PRESENT

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 Microsoft

## MARCH 2016 - MARCH 2018

Developing and Implementing Windowsbased Applications with Microsoft Visual Basic .NET and Microsoft Visual Studio .NET Microsoft